Guide to the Mathew B. Brady and Levin Corbin Handy Photographic Studios Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Levin Corbin Handy Studio, 1849-circa 1956; Series II; (28 boxes)
  - Original Photographs, (286 photographic prints)
    - Photographic Prints Created by the Levin Corbin Handy Studio, (373 photographic prints)
      - Photographic Prints of Exteriors in the District of Columbia, Washington
        - Constitution Gardens and the intersection of 17th Street SW and Constitution Avenue SW (Box 22, Folder 974)
        - Embassy of Germany (Box 22, Folder 975)
        - Embassy of Great Britain (Box 22, Folder 976)
        - Exterior portrait of sixteen pupils (seven boys and nine girls) transferring from the eighth grade to Jefferson High School, 1898 Sep 19 (Box 22, Folder 977)
        - From Arlington, Virginia, across the Lincoln Memorial Bridge to the Lincoln National Memorial (Box 22, Folder 978-979)
        - Funeral procession for President Warren Gamaliel Harding, 1923 Aug 8 (Box 22, Folder 980)
        - Georgetown. Francis Scott Key Mansion (Box 22, Folder 981)
        - Georgetown. M Street NW, funeral parade of Admiral Winfield Scott Schley, 1911 Oct 5 (Box 22, Folder 982)
        - Georgia Avenue NW and W Street NW. Construction of Griffith Stadium (identified in image as American League Park), 1911 Apr 6 (Box 22, Folder 983)
        - Horses on a boulevard; identified as the opening of Speedway (Box 22, Folder 984)
        - Inaugural parade of William McKinley, detail (Box 22, Folder 985)
        - Levin C. Handy Studio (Box 22, Folder 986)
        - Library of Congress. Neptune Plaza, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 987)
        - Library of Congress. Thomas Jefferson Building (Box 22, Folder 988)
        - Lincoln Memorial (Box 22, Folder 989)
        - Lincoln Park. Statue, Lincoln Freeing the Slaves by Thomas Bell, (3 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 990)
        - Maine Avenue SW between 6th Street and Capitol Avenue, flooded street (Box 22, Folder 991)
        - Maltby Building. New Jersey Avenue NW and Constitution Avenue NW, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 992)
        - Maltby Building from the United States Capitol Building (Box 22, Folder 993)
        - Maryland House, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 994)
        - National Academy of Sciences Building (Box 22, Folder 995)
        - National Woman's Party Building, formerly the Old Capitol Prison, 1st Street NE and A Street NE (Box 22, Folder 996)
        - Naval Observatory (Box 22, Folder 997)
        - New Jersey Avenue SE near the United States Capitol (Box 22, Folder 998)
        - Normandy Building, 15th Street NW and L Street NW, southeast corner (Box 22, Folder 999)
        - North from Rosslyn, Virginia, toward Georgetown University, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 1000)
        - Northeast from Arlington, Virginia (Box 22, Folder 1001)
        - Old Post Office Building, circa 1903 (Box 22, Folder 1002)
        - Old Tavern, corner of 7th Avenue SE and Pennsylvania Avenue SE (Box 22, Folder 1003)
        - Old United States Department of Justice Building (Box 22, Folder 1004)
        - Parade of the 49th Grand Army of the Republic Encampment, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 1005)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, 1400 block, including the Willard Hotel and New National Theatre (Box 22, Folder 1006)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, 300 block, showing the storefronts for J. William Lee, undertaker; George Mueller Candy Factory; and Hotel Berlin at No. 332, 336, and 338 (Box 22, Folder 1007)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, from Pershing Square toward the United States Capitol with the Old Post Office Building on the right, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 1008-1010)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, from the United States Capitol with the Old Post Office Building on the left, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 1011)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, parade for the Jockey Club races on in front of the Old Post Office Building, circa 1895 (Box 22, Folder 1012)
        - Pennsylvania Avenue NW, statue of Benjamin Franklin by Jacques Jouvenal in front of the Old Post Office Building (Box 22, Folder 1013)
        - Pennsylvania Railroad Station, looking south form the intersection of 6th Street SW and B (Independence) Avenue SW. Aftermath of the Johnstown Flood (Box 22, Folder 1014)
        - Petworth neighborhood. Girls pushing strollers, 1916 Jul 4 (Box 22, Folder 1015)
        - Railroad station on New York Avenue (Box 22, Folder 1016)
        - Residence of David Burns, oldest home in Washington (Box 22, Folder 1017)
        - Residence of John Marshall, 1801 F Street NW (Box 22, Folder 1018)
        - Residence of Melville Weston Fuller, 1800 Massachusetts Avenue (Box 22, Folder 1019)
        - Residence of Salmon Portland Chase, northwest corner of 6th Street NW and E Street NW (Box 22, Folder 1020)
        - Smithsonian Institution Building. South façade, west end (Box 22, Folder 1021)
        - South from the intersection of 7th Street NW and G Street NW, Smithsonian American Art Museum and the National Portrait Gallery (Box 22, Folder 1022)
        - State, War, and Navy Department Building (Box 22, Folder 1023)
        - Statue of George Washington by Horatio Greenough and the United States Capitol Building in the background, (2 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 1024)
        - Statue of George Washington by Horatio Greenough. Team of twelve horses and a wagon moving the statue (Box 22, Folder 1025)
        - Tenleytown neighborhood. Dumblane residence (Box 22, Folder 1026)
        - Thomas Circle and Luther Place Memorial Church, statue of George H. Thomas (Box 22, Folder 1027)
        - Unidentified building (Box 22, Folder 1028)
        - Union Station and Russell Senate Office Building. From the United States Capitol Building, (4 photographic prints) (Box 22, Folder 1029)
        - Union Station (Box 22, Folder 1030)
        - Union Station, circa 1907 (Box 22, Folder 1031)
        - United States Capitol Building, East Portico. Profile (Box 23, Folder 1032-1038)
        - United States Capitol Building, East Portico. Statue Rescue, by Horatio Greenough (Box 23, Folder 1039)
        - United States Capitol Building, West Portico. (Box 23, Folder 1040-1045)
        - United States Department of Justice Building from Constitution Avenue NW (Box 23, Folder 1046)
        - United States Internal Revenue Service Building (Box 23, Folder 1047)
        - United States Soldiers' Home. Geese on snow-covered landscape (Box 23, Folder 1048)
        - United States Treasury Building (Box 23, Folder 1049-1051)
        - United States Treasury Building in the background of a horse-drawn cab (Box 23, Folder 1052)
        - United States Treasury Building. Partial view of the north entrance (Box 23, Folder 1053)
        - Vicinity. Two men with a delivery truck for the Adams Express Company (Box 23, Folder 1054)
        - Virginia Avenue SW looking west at a railroad (Box 23, Folder 1055)
        - Washington Monument Grounds. Knights of Pythias encampment, 1894 (Box 23, Folder 1056)
        - West Potomac Park and wharves along the tidal basin (Box 23, Folder 1057)
        - White House from Lafayette Square at Pennsylvania Avenue NW (Box 23, Folder 1058)
        - White House from outside the East Wing to the north entrance (Box 23, Folder 1059-1060)
      - Photographic Prints of Exteriors Outside the District of Columbia
        - Illinois, New Salem (Menard County)
          - Denton Offutt store (Box 23, Folder 1061)
          - Henry Onstott cooper shop (Box 23, Folder 1062)
          - Hill-McNamer store (Box 23, Folder 1063)
          - Interior of the Lincoln League Museum (Box 23, Folder 1064)
          - Two girls draping a United States flag above a marker that designated the first home of Abraham Lincoln in Illinois (Box 23, Folder 1065)
          - Unidentified buildings (Box 23, Folder 1066)
        - Maryland, Bladensburg. Carlton Mill (Box 23, Folder 1067)
        - Maryland, Chesapeake Beach. Two oxen teams pulling wagons loaded with large barrels near a train for the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad (Box 23, Folder 1068)
        - Maryland, Sharpsburg. Dunker Church, 1915 Oct 24 (Box 23, Folder 1069)
        - New Jersey, Cape May. Photographic gallery of Chester and Handy, circa 1882 (Box 23, Folder 1070-1071)
        - Ohio, Cleveland. Public Auditorium (Box 23, Folder 1072)
        - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia. Liberty Bell (Box 23, Folder 1073)
        - Tennessee, Log cabin (Box 23, Folder 1074)
        - Virginia
          - Alexandria. Gadsby's Tavern (Box 23, Folder 1075)
          - Alexandria. Gadsby's Tavern, courtyard with colonial reenactors (Box 23, Folder 1076)
          - Elkton. Elk Spring with a group of men, women, and children (Box 23, Folder 1077)
          - Fishers Hill. Stone bridge and a building, (2 photographic prints) (Box 23, Folder 1078)
          - Fort Meyer. 6th United States Cavalry, Company E, preparing to leave for Cuba, 1898 Apr 19; (2 photographic prints) (Box 23, Folder 1079)
          - Fort Stevenson. Men and a woman at a Lincoln Memorial monument (Box 23, Folder 1080)
          - Great Falls. Old House (Box 23, Folder 1081)
          - Leesburg. Residence of George Head (Box 23, Folder 1082)
            Government archives held here during the burning of Washington, District of Columbia, in 1814
          - Leesburg. Residence of Louisa Brown, (2 photographic prints) (Box 23, Folder 1083)
          - Staffordshire County. Residence of Margaret Brent (Box 23, Folder 1084)
        - West Virginia
          - Charleston. "Happy Retreat," residence of Charles Washington (Box 23, Folder 1085)
          - Harpers Ferry. John Brown's Fort on the Alexander Murphy Farm, 1895-1909 (Box 23, Folder 1086)
            Three miles outside of town on a bluff overlooking the Shenandoah River
          - Morgan's Spring. Spring house. (Box 23, Folder 1087)
        - Unidentified locations
          - Portrait of the Anderson family, circa 1892 (Box 23, Folder 1088)
          - Portrait of a boy from the Rogers family (Box 23, Folder 1089)
          - Portrait of a group in front of building of the General Society of Colonial Wars, 1910 (Box 23, Folder 1090)
          - Thirty individuals (twenty-eight women and two men) posed standing on steps of a building, circa 1930 (Box 23, Folder 1091)
          - Twenty-three individuals (eighteen women and five men) posed standing on wooden stairs aside a building (Box 23, Folder 1092)
            Individuals identified on verso of print
          - Portrait of Herbert Clark Hoover aboard a ship (Box 23, Folder 1093)
          - Locomotive used on the Boston and Maine Railroad (Box 23, Folder 1094)
          - Locomotive, Old Faithful, No. 7100, circa 1923 (Box 23, Folder 1095)
          - Sculpture of a beardless Abraham Lincoln posed standing, (2 photographic prints) (Box 23, Folder 1096)
          - Unidentified locations, (39 photographic prints) (Box 23, Folder 1097)
      - Stereograph Cards, (13 cards)
        Arranged alphabetically by location, followed by unidentified locations.
        - District of Columbia, Washington
          - United States Capitol Building (Box 24, Folder 1098)
          - Washington Monument (Box 24, Folder 1099)
          - Washington Monument from water (Box 24, Folder 1100)
          - White House (Box 24, Folder 1101)
          - White House, interior of a corridor from the public entrance (Box 24, Folder 1102)
        - Massachusetts
          - Boston. Boston Public Library (Box 24, Folder 1103)
          - Charlestown. Bunker Hill Monument (Box 24, Folder 1104)
          - Lexington. Site of the colonial battlefield (Box 24, Folder 1105)
        - New York, New York. Hall of Fame for Great Americans (Box 24, Folder 1106)
        - Pennsylvania, Valley Forge. House that served as the headquarters of George Washington (Box 24, Folder 1107)
        - Unidentified locations
          - Log cabin (Box 24, Folder 1108)
          - River from above (Box 24, Folder 1109)
          - River with bridges from above (Box 24, Folder 1110)
      - Lantern Slides, (119 latern slides)
        Lantern slides of copy photographs of images created by photographers employed by the studio of Mathew B. Brady, that document persons and locations of the American Civil War, followed by images related to World War I, then by images related to excursions by the extended Handy family, then by images of Washington, D.C., and unidentified locations, and then followed by images of lithographs and artwork.
        - American Civil War Sites
          - District of Columbia. Washington. Officers of the 63rd New York Infantry (Box 25, Folder 1111)
          - District of Columbia. Washington. New York 17th Battery (Box 25, Folder 1112-1113)
          - Georgia, Atlanta. Overview (Box 25, Folder 1114)
          - Georgia, Atlanta. After capture (Box 25, Folder 1115)
          - Georgia, Atlanta. Destruction of the ordinance train of John Bell Hood, 1864 (Box 25, Folder 1116)
          - Georgia, Atlanta. William Tecumseh Sherman and his staff (Box 25, Folder 1117)
          - Maryland, Sharpsburg. Battlefield (Box 25, Folder 1118)
          - Maryland, Sharpsburg. Dead gathered for burial, 1862 Sep 17 (Box 25, Folder 1119)
          - Maryland, Sharpsburg. Exterior painted portrait of Abraham Lincoln and George Brinton McClellan (Box 25, Folder 1120)
          - Mississippi River. Gun boat (Box 25, Folder 1121)
          - Pennsylvania, Gettysburg. Entrance to the national cemetery (Box 25, Folder 1122)
          - Tennessee, Murfreesboro. Monument to the Battle of Stones River (Box 25, Folder 1123)
          - Virginia, Alexandria. Marshall House boarding house (Box 25, Folder 1124)
          - Virginia, Alexandria. Slave pen (Box 25, Folder 1125)
          - Virginia, Bealeton. Exterior portrait of the regimental staff of 93rd New York, 1863 (Box 25, Folder 1126)
          - Virginia, Brandy Station. Dinner party outside tent, Army of the Potomac headquarters (Box 25, Folder 1127)
          - Virginia, Brandy Station. Discussing the probabilities of the next move (Box 25, Folder 1128)
          - Virginia, Brandy Station. Log kitchen of the 6th New York Artillery (Box 25, Folder 1129)
          - Virginia, Bull Run. Confederate fortification (Box 25, Folder 1130)
          - Virginia, Centreville. Winter quarters of the Confederate Army, 1862 Mar (Box 25, Folder 1131)
          - Virginia, Chickahominy River. Crossing the grapevine bridge, 1862 Jun (Box 25, Folder 1132)
          - Virginia, City Point. Exterior portrait of Joseph Hooker mounted on a horse (Box 25, Folder 1133)
          - Virginia, City Point. General hospital (Box 25, Folder 1134)
          - Virginia, City Point. Officers of the 80th New York, 1863 Sep (Box 25, Folder 1135)
          - Virginia, Fair Oaks. Prof. Thaddeus S. Lowe observing the battle from his balloon Intrepid (Box 25, Folder 1136)
          - Virginia, Fredericksburg. Dr. Bunnell's embalming establishment in the field (Box 25, Folder 1137)
          - Virginia, James River. 100 pounder on Confederate gunboat Teazer captured on July 4, 1862 by U.S.S. Maratanza (Box 25, Folder 1138)
          - Virginia, James River. Pontoon Bridge (Box 25, Folder 1139)
          - Virginia, Rappahannock Station. Quarters of field and staff of 50th New York Engineers (Box 25, Folder 1140)
          - Virginia, Rappahannock Station. Sutler hut and stockade of 50th New York Engineers (Box 25, Folder 1141)
          - Virginia, Petersburg. Bomb proof (Box 25, Folder 1142)
          - Virginia, Petersburg. Dictator gun (Box 25, Folder 1143)
          - Virginia, Petersburg. Exterior portrait. Winfield Scott Hancock, John Gibbon, Francis Channing Barlow and William Birney (Box 25, Folder 1144)
          - Virginia, Petersburg. Officers Massachusetts Cavalry, 1864 (Box 25, Folder 1145)
          - Virginia, Petersburg. Signal tower, 1864 (Box 25, Folder 1146)
          - Virginia, Uptown Hill. George Brinton McClellan and Staff (Box 25, Folder 1147)
          - Virginia, Unidentified location. Mule team crossing a creek (Box 25, Folder 1148)
          - Unidentified location. Burning railroad ties and rails (Box 25, Folder 1149)
          - Unidentified location. Cooking in camp (Box 25, Folder 1150)
          - Unidentified location. Exploded shell (Box 25, Folder 1151)
          - Unidentified location. Philip Henry Sheridan and other generals in front of his tent, 1864. Left to right: Wesley Merritt, David McMurtrie Gregg, Sheridan, Henry E. Davies (standing), James Harrison Wilson, and Alfred Thomas Archimedes Torbert (Box 25, Folder 1152)
        - American Civil War Studio Portraits
          - Andrew, John Albion (Box 25, Folder 1153)
            Governor of Massachusetts
          - Brady, Mathew B. (Box 25, Folder 1154)
          - Carson, Christopher Houston "Kit" (Box 25, Folder 1155)
          - Curtin, Andrew Gregg (Box 25, Folder 1156)
          - Custer, George Armstrong (Box 25, Folder 1157)
          - Farragut, David Glasgow (Box 25, Folder 1158)
          - Fish, Hamilton (Box 25, Folder 1159)
          - Grant, Ulysses S. (Box 25, Folder 1160)
          - Hancock, Winfield Scott (Box 25, Folder 1161)
          - Heintzelman, Samuel Peter (Box 26, Folder 1162)
          - Lee, Robert Edward (Box 26, Folder 1163)
          - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 26, Folder 1164)
          - Lincoln, Abraham, and Thomas "Tad" Lincoln (Box 26, Folder 1165)
          - McClellan, George Brinton (Box 26, Folder 1166)
          - Meade, George Gordon (Box 26, Folder 1167)
          - Morton, Oliver Hazard Perry Throck (Box 26, Folder 1168)
          - Porter, David Dixon (Box 26, Folder 1169)
          - Sheridan, Philip Henry (Box 26, Folder 1170)
          - Sherman, William Tecumseh, and his staff (Box 26, Folder 1171)
          - Slocum, Henry Warner, and his staff (Box 26, Folder 1172)
          - Stanton, Edwin McMasters (Box 26, Folder 1173)
          - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton (Box 26, Folder 1174)
          - Thomas, George Henry (Box 26, Folder 1175)
          - Tilden, Samuel Jones (Box 26, Folder 1176)
            Governor of New York
        - World War I
          Arranged by the numbers assigned to the images
          - 6. Soldiers exercising (Box 26, Folder 1177)
          - 13. Airplane looping the loop (Box 26, Folder 1178)
          - 15. What the navy can do for your boy (Box 26, Folder 1179)
          - 22. American fighters go over the top (Box 26, Folder 1180)
          - 30. Harry A. Menge (Box 26, Folder 1181)
          - 32. Dr. Joe Stout (Box 26, Folder 1182)
          - 33. Joseph F. Stone (Box 26, Folder 1183)
          - 34. Millard H. Sutton (Box 26, Folder 1184)
          - 35. Thomas Vickers (Box 26, Folder 1185)
          - 36. Virgil Young, master engineer, and wife (Box 26, Folder 1186)
          - 37. Lieutenant Yount (Box 26, Folder 1187)
          - 38. Raymond Papkins (Box 26, Folder 1188)
          - 39. Alvard Rowans (Box 26, Folder 1189)
          - 43. Rheims, allegorical drawing (Box 26, Folder 1190)
          - 57.5. Signal corps (Box 26, Folder 1191)
          - 60. Statement soliciting books for soldiers (Box 26, Folder 1192)
          - 67. Original Star-Spangled Banner (Box 26, Folder 1193)
          - Soldiers reading (Box 26, Folder 1194)
          - Virginia, Camp Lee, Soldiers reading (Box 26, Folder 1195)
        - Handy family images
          - Camp from Emmett Hill (Box 26, Folder 1196)
          - Camp, tents of Caspar, Will, and John (Box 26, Folder 1197)
          - Family holding suitcases; homeward bound (Box 26, Folder 1198)
          - Family in camp; guiding stars (Box 26, Folder 1199)
          - Family in camp; keep still Ashley (Box 26, Folder 1200)
          - Three men holding a line of fish, camp, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 1201)
        - District of Columbia, Washington
          - Library of Congress, floor plan, second floor (Box 26, Folder 1202)
          - Store of John Imirie, 184 6th Street SW (Box 76, Folder 1203)
            Conditions Governing Access
            Restricted: Fragile, broken plate
        - Unidentified locations
          - Christmas Tree (Box 26, Folder 1204)
          - Mrs. Maple in wedding dress (Box 26, Folder 1205)
          - Snow-covered streets (Box 26, Folder 1206)
          - Woodrow Wilson holding a child (Box 26, Folder 1207)
        - Artwork
          - Abraham Lincoln family, lithograph (Box 26, Folder 1208)
          - Father, Savior, and Preserver of the Constitution, artwork (Box 26, Folder 1209)
          - Object, Universal Roll of Honor (Box 26, Folder 1210-1211)
          - Three boys, art work (Box 27, Folder 1212)
          - Two women and a girl, artwork (Box 27, Folder 1213)
          - Woman, artwork (Box 27, Folder 1214)
        - Arabic Writing (Box 27, Folder 1215)
        - Chinese Art
          - Boat by pier with figures on an island (Box 27, Folder 1216)
          - Boats on tree-lined water (Box 27, Folder 1217)
          - Boats on water (Box 27, Folder 1218-1219)
          - Figure (Box 27, Folder 1220)
          - Figures on road by trees (Box 27, Folder 1221)
          - Landscape (Box 27, Folder 1222-1224)
          - Tree (Box 27, Folder 1225)
        - Eastern Indian Art
          - Ceramic (Box 27, Folder 1226)
          - Painting (Box 27, Folder 1227)
        - Persian Art
          - Painting (Box 27, Folder 1228)
          - Painting and calligraphy (Box 27, Folder 1229)
          - Pottery (Box 27, Folder 1230)
  - Copy Photographs, (430 photographic prints)
    This series consists of photographic prints produced by photographing a two-dimensional work, such as a drawing or painting, or by creating a photograph of another photograph.
    The copy photographs are arranged with copies of photographs followed by copies of artwork and mechanical prints, and then by copies of paintings of signatories of the Declaration of Independence and the United States Constitution.
    - Photographic Prints of Copy Photographs, (80 photographic prints)
      Copy photographs of primarily historical subjects.
      Arranged alphabetically by geographical location of the subject, followed by portraits, arranged alphabetically by the surname of the subject.
      - District of Columbia, Washington
        - 14th Street NW on Florida Avenue NW, Horse-drawn streetcar just east (Box 28, Folder 1231)
        - Ebbitt House, 14th Street NW and F Street NW (Box 28, Folder 1232)
        - Funeral locomotive, Nashville, that transported the body of Abraham Lincoln (Box 28, Folder 1233)
        - Georgetown. Signal camp on Red Hill (Box 28, Folder 1234)
        - Noerr's National Bakery at the southwest corner of 11 Street NW and E Street NW (Box 28, Folder 1235)
        - United States Capitol Building. Exterior. Dome under construction, circa 1860, (5 photographic prints) (Box 28, Folder 1236)
        - United States Patent Office Building, (3 photographic prints) (Box 28, Folder 1237)
        - United States State Department Building, S Street NW and 14th Streets NW, circa 1866 (Box 28, Folder 1238)
        - Willard Hotel (Box 28, Folder 1239)
      - District of Columbia, Mason's Island. Guards at ferry landing examining a pass (Box 28, Folder 1240)
      - Florida, Pensacola. Fort McRee. Confederate troops drilling, (3 photographic prints) (Box 28, Folder 1241)
      - Georgia, Andersonville Prison. Giving out rations (Box 28, Folder 1242)
      - Kentucky, Nolin Creek. Cabin identified as the birthplace of Abraham Lincoln, (3 photographic prints) (Box 28, Folder 1243)
      - Maryland, Bryantown. Residence of Samuel Alexander Mudd (Box 28, Folder 1244)
      - Maryland, Poolesville. Soldiers on a street, (2 photographic prints) (Box 28, Folder 1245)
      - Maryland, Sharpsburg